<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[evertvdbruel blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://evertvdbruel.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://evertvdbruel.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-13T16:44:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://evertvdbruel.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Evertvdbruel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix outside America?]]></title>
    <link href="http://evertvdbruel.com/blog/2013/01/08/netflix/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T19:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://evertvdbruel.com/blog/2013/01/08/netflix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Getting American flavoured internet</h2>

<p>A few weeks ago I was wondering if it was possible to use Netflix in Belgium, so I started searching the web for ways to achieve this.</p>

<p>I came across quite a VPN services during this quest but the one that looked the most promising to me <a href="http://hidemyass.com/vpn/r9744">hidemyass.com</a> (please note that is a referral link). One of the main reasons that I chose hidemyass was that you can configure it on a router so it&#8217;s possible to use Netflix(or any other country limited service) on your Playstation, Xbox, Apple TV,&#8230; but you can just install the client on your computer and use your browser.</p>

<p>If you want to use a router for this you need that you can flash DD-WRT on (you can check it <a href="http://www.dd-wrt.com/site/support/router-database">here</a>). Since I didn&#8217;t have an old router I started looking online for a cheap router that I could use and bought the <a href="http://www.tp-link.com/en/products/details/?model=TL-WR1043ND">TP-Link TL-WR1043ND</a> on <a href="http://partnerprogramma.bol.com/click/click?p=1&amp;t=url&amp;s=17363&amp;url=http%3A//www.bol.com/nl/p/tp-link-tl-wr1043nd-300mbps-wireless-router/1003004011473203/&amp;f=TXL&amp;name=router">Bol.com</a>.
Next I flashed the DD-WRT firmware on the router using the instructions found <a href="http://www.dd-wrt.com/wiki/index.php/Installation">here</a>.  After that I configured the hidemyass settings on the router like <a href="http://wiki.hidemyass.com/DD-WRT_L2TP_Setup">this</a>.
When everything is setup correctly you can start exploring the American internet.</p>

<p>By default the Netflix application is hidden on most non-American devices I guess for not frustrating users with an unusable app so you need to change the region to USA.</p>

<ul>
<li>Apple TV: Settings > General > iTunes Store > Location and choose United States</li>
<li>Playstation 3: <a href="http://us.playstation.com/psn/">create a new ps network account</a> and choose United States as region, log in on your device and download Netflix</li>
</ul>


<p>The only thing left before you can start enjoying the Netflix goodness is registering an <a href="http://netflix.com">account</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://evertvdbruel.com/images/suggestions.png"></p>

<h2>Thoughts after one month</h2>

<p>I&#8217;m realy loving every moment I&#8217;m using my setup here are some reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>the amount of content with stuff like:

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0903747/">Breaking Bad</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1124373/">Sons of Anarchy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0086662/">Airwolf</a></li>
<li>&#8230;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rlZUsPcChgI">Netflix original content</a> (coming soon)</li>
<li>pickup where you left in your on &#8216;any&#8217; device</li>
<li>access other exclusive content like the US google play store, so you can get books, movies, &#8230; on your Android</li>
<li>content starts at the press of a button</li>
<li>allmost everything has English subtitles</li>
<li>recommendations on things to see based on your ratings</li>
</ul>


<p>And a few negative points:</p>

<ul>
<li>Netflix hasn&#8217;t got all the content :], but there are other services like hulu, hbo, &#8230; so you can get extra content if you like</li>
<li>due to the latency surfing isn&#8217;t a solid experience (no problems with streaming)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Watching content never has been easier for me fire up the application, select the video you want to watch, press play and you&#8217;re done. So I would recommend using netflix to anyone who loves consuming tons of content.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
